gatorade.com 2016-05-30

# Gatorade.com Privacy Policy

### 5/20/2016

## THIS PRIVACY POLICY APPLIES TO SEVERAL OF OUR SITES AND APPS

This policy describes our privacy practices for the websites where it is posted. This includes mobile websites. This policy also describes our practices on our smart phone applications. By accessing or using our websites or apps you consent to this policy.

This policy does not apply to information we might collect in other situations, like offline or by email. This policy also does not apply to the practices of third parties who may provide services or features on our websites or apps.

This policy is effective as of May 20th, 2016. 

To download a copy of this full privacy policy, see below.

We may update this privacy policy at any time effective upon its posting.

## INFORMATION WE COLLECT.

We may collect contact and personal information. For example, we might collect your name, address, email address, and phone number.

Payment information. If you make purchases, we might collect your credit card information.

We also collect information you submit, share or post. For example if you post content such as comments, videos or photos, we will collect the information you provide to us. We will also collect information you submit regarding your sports, athletic goals, teams and game. We may also collect information you provide about your performance tests and physical and nutritional activity. 

We collect information you provide about your friends. For example, if you provide your friend's name and e-mail address through a send-a-friend feature on a site or app. 

We collect information about your device and Internet usage. If you download one of  our applications, we may collect information from your phone, like your UDID. We may also collect information about the parts of our app you use or third party apps or websites you visit when you leave our own. We may work with third parties who collect information about you when you use our apps. 

Demographic information. We might also ask for information like your gender and age.

Depending on the features you use, we may collect information about your location. When accessing a site or application from a mobile device, we might use cellular tower information to identify your approximate location. We might also work with third parties who collect this information through our apps or websites.

Other information. If you use our websites, we may collect information about the browser you are using. We might track the pages you visit. We might look at what site you came from, or what site you visit when you leave us. We collect this information using the tracking tools described here. To control those tools, please read below.

## WE COLLECT INFORMATION FROM THIRD PARTIES, AND PASSIVELY.

We collect information from you passively. We (or vendors acting on our behalf) use common collection techniques. For example, we might use digital fingerprinting, browser cookies or web beacons. We might also use cookies or other common tools. Our vendors might also use scripts or other tools to track your activities. To learn more about these tools and how you can control them, see below.

We get information about you from third parties. For example, social media platforms that you connect to may give us information about you.

## WE USE INFORMATION TO PROVIDE THE FEATURES IN OUR APPS AND AS DESCRIBED HERE.

We use information to respond to your requests or questions. For example we may use your information to register you for a contest or giveaway or to communicate with you regarding an order. We may also use your information to provide you with training and nutrition suggestions.

We use your information to help us improve our products and services. For example, we might look at usage trends to make sure our sites and apps are easy to use. We may also use information to customize your browsing experience.

For security purposes. We may use information to protect our company, our customers, or our websites.

For our legitimate business purposes. For example, we may send you emails about your account or changes to our sites, applications, or policies. We may also combine information that we receive about you from third parties with information we already have.

We use your information for marketing purposes. For example, if we have your contact information, we might send you marketing messages. Third parties we work with may use your UDID to help us serve you with ads targeted to your interests.

## WE MAY SHARE INFORMATION WITH THIRD PARTIES.

If we think we have to in order to comply with the law. For example, we will share information to respond to a court order or subpoena. We may also share if a government agency requests. We may also share if an investigatory body requests.

With third parties who perform services on our behalf. For example, they may handle credit card processing.  We share information with vendors. We may also authorize them to collect information on our behalf. For example, our vendors may collect information for anonymous data reporting. Some vendors may be located outside of the United States.

With our business partners. If we provide joint services, we may share your information with our business partners.

With third parties providing functionality. For example, we may share information with Facebook when you “connect” with them.

With our affiliated companies. The Gatorade Company is a part of PepsiCo., Inc. (“Pepsi Brands”). Pepsi Brands include Pepsi Cola, Frito Lay, Quaker Oats, and Tropicana. For a full list, visit www.pepsico.com. We may share your information with any of these or future Pepsi Brands.

In the event of a change in corporate ownership. For example, if part of our business was sold we may sell our customer list as part of that transaction.

For other reasons we may describe to you.

## YOU HAVE CERTAIN CHOICES ABOUT OUR MARKETING AND TRACKING TOOLS.

You can opt out of marketing messages. To stop getting our marketing emails, follow the instructions in any message you receive. You can also opt-out by emailing us

You can turn off or manage many of the tracking tools we use. To do so, following the instructions in your phone or website browser settings. You can also reject certain permissions requests posed by our apps and platforms. If you do this, some of the features of our apps and platforms will not work. If you delete your cookies or use a different browser, you will need to renew your opt-out choice. You will also have to redo your opt-out choice if you use a different computer or a different phone. In some cases not all of our features or apps will function properly if you turn off tracking.

You can control cookies and tracking tools. To learn how to manage how we - and our vendors - use cookies and other tracking tools, please see About our Ads.

You have other controls you can exercise. You can choose whether or not to share personal information. If you choose not to share, some parts of our sites and some services may be more difficult or impossible to use. If you turn off cookies or tracking tools, parts of our site and services may also not work properly.

You can uninstall a mobile application. You can stop all collection of information by one of our mobile applications easily by uninstalling the application. You may use the standard uninstall processes as may be available as part of your mobile device or via the mobile application marketplace or network.

## WE STORE INFORMATION IN THE UNITED STATES.

Our sites and servers may be located in the United States. If you are outside of the U.S., your information may be sent to the United States. By using our sites and applications, and by giving us your information, you consent to such transfer. You also understand that the U.S. may not provide you with as much protections as the laws of your country.

## WE USE STANDARD SECURITY MEASURES.

We use standard security measures on our sites and apps. However, the internet is a public place. We cannot promise that your information will remain secure. We encourage you to use caution when sharing information. Do not share your password with other people and pick secure passwords.

## THIS APPLICATION OR WEBSITE IS NOT INTENDED FOR KIDS.

Our apps and websites are not designe for kids , and we do not to our knowledge collect information from children under 13 on this app. If you are a parent or guardian and think we have information about your child, please contact us by email. You may also write us at the address listed below. Please mark your inquiries to the attention of “COPPA - Information Request” and include your email and phone number.

To learn more about how to protect your child online, visit the FTC's website. You may also want to read the helpful information about kids and privacy that the FTC provides.

## THIS APP OR SITE MAY HAVE LINKS TO THIRD PARTY APPS OR SERVICES WE DON'T CONTROL.

Our sites and applications contain links to third party sites. If you click on one of those links, you will be taken to sites we do not control. This policy does not apply to the practices of that site. You should read third party privacy policies carefully.

## CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS

If you reside in California, you have the right to ask us one time each year if we have shared personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To exercise your rights, you can email us or write to us at the address in the “More Questions” section, above. Mention in your letter that you are making a "California Shine the Light" inquiry. We will respond as required by law.

## FEEL FREE TO CONTACT US IF YOU HAVE MORE QUESTIONS.

If you have additional questions you can call the webmaster at 1-800-88-GATOR (1-800-884-2867) or reach us by email. You can also write to us at:

The Gatorade Company  
P.O. Box 049003 Chicago, IL 60604-9003  
Attention: Webmaster - Privacy Inquiry

Please include your email address, name, address and telephone number when you contact us. This helps us handle your request correctly.
